## JIHYE CHOI

San Jose, CA | 714-290-2032 | jihye1023@gmail.com linkedin.com/jihyechoi1023/ | github.com/jhye1023

#### SUMMARY

Data analyst with a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley Extension and 6+ years of experience in the financial industry. Experienced in reporting with data to facilitate executive-level decision making. Maintaining priorities on strict deadlines and a fast learner who can absorb new ideas and skills. Finds great satisfaction in extracting insights from data that inform decision-making and drive growth.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Flask, Matplotlib, API, JavaScript, JSON, HTML, CSS, D3, SQL, SQL Alchemy, MongoDB, Tableau, Microsoft Office

### **PROJECTS**

## Language Demographic in the US | https://github.com/tomrecht/Project-1|

- Explored recent trends in the population of speakers of foreign languages in the US, both nationally and at the regional level.
- Used the American Community Survey 1-Year Data API for getting data and using Pandas and Matplotlib for data cleaning and creating charts.
- Pandas, Matplotlib, Census Module, Gmaps and Numpy were used to gather data and create charts.

## **New York Property Sales - Still working**

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# AVP & Accounting Officer Open Bank

July 2015 - February 2020 Los Angeles, CA

- Prepared financial reports package for senior management presentation.
- Analyzed income statement including reconciliation of actual with projections and variance analysis.
- Managed and kept developing complex excel-based financial worksheets so reduced time to create financial reports by 50%.
- Updated and implemented new procedures to enhance the workflow of the accounting department.

## **Accounting Supervisor**

September 2013 - June 2015

US Metro Bank

Garden Grove, CA

- Assisted in various accounting activities, including account payable, journal entry, bank account reconciliation and auditing.
- Supported monthly financial closing by collecting documents and ensuring all financial deadlines was met.

### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley
Analytics and Visualization Certificate
University of California, San Diego
Bachelor of Arts in Economics, minor in Accounting

Berkeley, CA February 2020 - August 2020 San Diego, CA